[ buzzing ]
[ low-pitched rumbling ]
I sent you 20 letters from Paris last year
Well , you 've been gone six months
And I got the fear
After all the songs that we 've sung together
After all the sweet and all the stormy ...
[ rumbling continues ]
If I knew where you were
Well , I would surely inform you that ...
But every night don 't you
- I Sleep on your right ? - [ tires screech ]
Don 't you ...
[ evil laughter ]
Hey , Ash , where are we ?
Well , we just crossed the Tennessee border .
- Which would put us ... - Yeah ?
[ low-pitched buzzing ]
Which would put us ...
right ...
- here . - [ brakes squeal ]
[ truck horn honking ]
Turn !
- [ honking ] - [ screaming ]
What the hell was that ? Are you trying to kill us ?
Hey , don 't blame me ! It 's your steering wheel .
The damn thing jerked right out of my hand !
I don 't understand , I had this thing in for a tune-up yesterday
and they said they 'd go over everything .
Yeah , well , you 'd better take it back ' cause the damn thing don 't work .
The only thing that does work is this lousy horn .
[ honking ]
Aw , go to hell ! I 'm not honking at you !
[ laughing ] Jesus Christ .
[ woman ] Hey , Scotty , what 's this place like anyway ?
Well , the guy that 's renting it says it 's an old place - -
a little run down , but it 's right up in the mountains .
And the best part is we get it so cheap .
Yeah , why are we getting it so cheap ?
Well , I don 't know . Might be in real bad shape .
You mean , nobody 's seen this place yet ?
Well , not yet .
- Well , it might not be that bad . - No .
- Actually , it might be kinda nice . - Yeah .
It 's probably a real pit .
Hey , I think this is where we get off .
[ woman ] This is the bridge we 're gonna cross ?
[ Ash ] Jesus Christ , the whole thing 's falling apart on us !
[ Scotty ] Don 't let the noise fool you , girls . This thing is solid as a rock .
[ woman screams ]
[ Scotty laughing ]
J
[ slow banging sound ]
[ louder banging ]
[ banging ]
[ banging continues ]
[ banging stops ]
It 's supposed to be one of these on here .
[ door creaks ]
J
- Come on . Hey ! Hey ! - Hey !
- [ grunts ] - Hey . [ laughs ]
J
[ crickets chirping ]
[ ticking ]
[ ticking stops , clock chimes ]
- [ wind howling ] - [ distorted I Join us .
Join us ...
[ banging ]
[ gasps ]
[ wind stops ]
[ banging stops ]
[ whispering ] Dead bodies in the cellar .
- Dead bodies in the cellar . - Will you stop it ?
I would like very much to make a toast here for all this evening .
- [ Scotty ] Yeah . - That sounds all right .
Uh , as a Greek friend of mine once said ...
he said , " I ... "
- [ woman giggles ] - No , okay , okay , okay .
- " Nis , nis - - - [ laughing ]
tu - - tu - - tu-tar-im . "
- Which means ? - " Party down . " Yeah !
[ bang ]
J
What is this ?
Whatever it is , it 's still down there .
I don 't like cellars . Let 's just close it up .
It 's probably just some animal .
An animal ? An animal ? ! [ laughs ]
That is the stupidest thing I ever heard of .
Jesus Christ .
Well , there 's something down there .
Well , maybe it is just some animal .
Yeah , you 're probably right . It 's probably just some animal .
Here , Cheryl . Why don 't you go down and check to make sure ?
Scotty , I 'm not going down there !
Okay okay , you cowards . I 'll go .
Be careful .
Back in a minute .
Hey - - hey , Scotty , you find anything ?
Scotty ?
Scotty !
Scott !
He 's just kidding around .
- Isn 't he ? - Scotty !
Scott ! Linda , get me a flashlight .
Well , that 's the only one we brought up .
Then get the lantern .
J
Scotty ?
[ door slamming ]
[ door creaking ]
- Boo ! [ laughs ] - [ yelps ]
Hey , come here . I want to show you something .
Look at all this stuff .
I bet this still shoots .
Probably does .
- Oh ! God ! - [ laughs ]
Oh , God .
Look at this .
This kind of looks like your old girlfriend . [ laughs ]
Come on , let 's take this stuff upstairs .
I 'll grab the recorder and you get everything else .
[ Ash ] Yeah , okay .
J
[ Scotty ] This guy was a real turd , you know ?
Everybody hated him .
Like you kind of , right ?
Yeah , just like me . I 'm gonna break your face .
Also , he was into this Western stuff .
He makes all these little models - -
Okay , shh . Listen to this .
This is the tape I found downstairs .
[ man on tape ] It has been a number of years
since I began excavating the ruins of Ca 'n Dar with a group of my colleagues .
Now my wife and I have retreated to a small cabin
in the solitude of these mountains .
Here I continued my research undisturbed
by the myriad distractions of modern civilization
and far from the groves of academe .
I believe I have made a significant find in the Ca 'n Darian ruins :
a volume of ancient Sumerian burial practices
and funerary incantations .
It is entitled Naturan Demanto .
Roughly translated - - " Book of the Dead . "
The book is bound in human flesh and inked in human blood .
[ thunderclap ]
It deals with demons , demon resurrection ,
and those forces which roam the forest and dark bowers of man 's domain .
- [ thunder continues ] - The first few pages warn
that these enduring creatures may lie dormant ,
but are never truly dead .
They may be recalled to active life
through the incantations presented in this book .
It is through recitation of these passages
that the demons are given license to possess the living .
Hey , what 'd you do that for ? It was just getting good .
I just don 't wanna hear it anymore , that 's all .
[ imitating ghostly moaning ]
[ Ash ] Scott , come on . Leave her alone , man .
Hey , come on . I just wanna hear the rest of it .
No big deal .
[ man on tape ] Tantir-ah-mis-trobeen-ha-zar-ta .
Tantir-manov -
mansis-hazen-sober .
Saman-ta-roza-dar-hiz-hikar - dan-derodza .
Kanda .
Shut it off .
Kanda !
[ screaming ] Shut it off !
- [ screams ] - Oh , my God !
- [ crying ] - Cheryl .
- Where are you going ? - I can 't believe this .
Scott , you knew not to play that .
I mean , come on , you knew it was upsetting her .
You just don 't know when you 're taking something too far .
Hey , don 't give me that . You were playing it , too .
You could have shut it off .
I mean , big deal ! She 's nuts .
I mean , it 's just a joke . Come on .
- [ kicks broken glass ] - Jesus Christ ,
she acts like she 's three years old or something .
[ thunderclap ]
Listen , why don 't we stay up for a while and listen to the storm ?
All right , yeah .
Let me check on Cheryl first to make sure she 's okay .
Okay .
J
A-ha !
- Oh ! Stealing from the blind , huh ? - [ giggles ]
It 's for you .
Ash , how sweet of you .
- Would you put it on ? - Oh , sure .
I was gonna give it to you before we came up here ,
but things got so hectic .
This is really the first chance we 've had to be alone .
Take a look .
Oh , Ash , it 's beautiful .
I really love it . I 'll never take it off .
[ low-pitched rumble ]
[ rumble continues ]
[ low-pitched distorted voice ] Join us ...
Is anybody out there ?
[ animal howls ]
I know someone 's out there .
I heard you . I heard you in the cellar .
[ echoing crackle ]
[ underbrush crashing ]
[ low-pitched groaning ]
[ screams ]
[ growling ]
[ crashing ]
[ distorted voice ] Join us .
[ buzzing , swarming sounds ]
[ screams ]
[ screaming continues ]
[ fabric ripping ]
[ low-pitched rumbling ]
[ crying out ]
- [ rumbling stops ] - [ grunts , groans ]
- [ screaming ] - [ underbrush crashing ]
Help !
[ rumbling resumes ]
[ panting ]
[ screaming ]
Ashley !
Help !
The keys .
[ heart pounding ]
[ heart pounding faster ]
Help !
J
[ screams ]
[ distorted moaning ]
- [ Scotty ] What the hell happened to you ? - Yeah , what 's the matter with you ?
Did something in the woods do this to you ?
No , it was the woods themselves .
They 're alive , Ashley . The trees , they 're alive !
Ash , why don 't I take her in the back room so she can lie down ?
I 'm not lying down ! I wanna get out of here !
I wanna leave this place right now .
- Right now , Ashley . - Wait a minute .
I sure as hell am not leaving any place tonight .
- Cheryl . - Cheryl .
Cheryl , there 's nothing out there . Trees do not attack people .
Ashley , will you drive me into town or not ?
What , right now ?
Yeah . Look , sure , sure , I 'll take you into town ,
- but just listen to what you 're saying . - I don 't care how it sounds .
I wanna get out of this place right now .
Okay , you can stay somewhere in town tonight .
[ crickets chirping ]
[ engine cranking ]
Come on , come on , come on .
[ ignition clicks off ]
[ engine cranking ]
I know it 's not gonna start . It 's not gonna let us leave .
[ engine starts ]
J
Why are you stopping ?
Wait here a minute .
J
Do you see something ?
Where you going ? !
Ashley ?
[ yelps ]
Oh ! Oh !
[ screams ]
- It 's not gonna let us go ! - What ?
It 's not gonna let us go ! I told you !
I told you , it 's not gonna let us go !
Why won 't you listen to me ?
[ sobbing ]
[ man on tape ] I know now that my wife has become host to a Ca " n Darian demon .
I fear that the only way to stop those possessed by the spirits of the book
is through the act of bodily dismemberment .
I would leave now to avoid this horror , but for myself I - -
I have seen the dark shadows moving in the woods ,
and I have no doubt that whatever I have resurrected through this book
is sure to come calling for me .
Okay , let me think . Um ... It 's a seven .
- What suit ? - Um ... diamonds .
No , no , no , wait . Uh , hearts .
Oh my God . Seven of hearts , you 're right .
Hey , Ash , I guessed the card right .
Yeah , truly amazing , Linda .
I don 't know , I don 't know ,
but I think it 's really some sort of extra sense or something .
- You know , like ESP ? - Okay , try this .
- Okay , um ... it 's a seven . - I don 't believe it .
[ Cheryl ] Of spades - - queen of spades .
Four of hearts ,
eight of spades ,
[ voice distorting ] two of spades , jack of diamonds ,
jack of clubs . [ growls ]
[ screams ]
[ distorted voices ] Why have you disturbed our sleep ,
awakened us from our ancient slumber ?
You will die like the others before you !
One by one , we will take you .
[ growls ]
[ gasps ]
What happened to her ?
Cheryl ?
Did you see her eyes ?
Ash , I 'm scared . What 's wrong with her ?
J
[ shrieks ]
[ screaming ]
[ shrieking ]
Cheryl , stop it !
[ distorted voices ] Join us . Join us ...
[ voices grunting ]
[ pounding ]
[ voices fade away ]
[ crickets chirping ]
[ distorted grunting ]
[ door opens ]
[ Scotty ] Ash , I think we ought to get out of here .
- Yeah . - [ grunting continues ]
We still have a few more hours before morning .
[ Shelly ] I don 't think I can wait that long .
You have to . We all have to .
And then in the morning , we 'll get in the car
and we 'll take the bridge .
- And ... - [ grunting continues ]
Why does she keep making those horrible noises ?
[ Ash ] I don 't know !
What about her eyes ?
- What about her eyes ? - [ grunting , wheezing ]
For God 's sake , what happened to her eyes ? !
[ cackling ]
[ low-pitched rumbling ]
Everything 's gonna be all right .
Scotty , I - - I think there 's something out there .
[ low-pitched rumbling ]
Go to bed and get some sleep , okay ?
[ rumbling increases ]
[ screams ]
[ clattering ]
Shelly ?
[ choking ]
[ screaming ]
[ distorted voice screaming ]
No ! Don 't burn her ! Get her out !
[ shrieking ] No !
[ multiple voices ] Thank you .
I don 't know what I would have done
if I had remained on those hot coals ,
burning my pretty flesh .
You have pretty skin .
Give it to us !
[ gagging ]
[ growling ]
Join us ! Join us !
Join us !
[ shrieking ] No , no , no !
[ bones crunching ]
[ low growl ]
[ shrieking ]
[ knife hilt screaming ]
[ shrieking fades ]
[ grunting ]
[ growls ]
[ shrieks ]
Hit her .
Hit her !
Hit it !
Let go ! No , no !
[ shrieking ] You love her ! No !
No , you love her ! Don 't do it !
[ grunting ]
[ panting ]
Scott ?
Yeah ?
What is - - what are we gonna do ?
We 're gonna bury her .
You can 't bury Shelly .
- She 's a - - she 's a friend of ours . - Ash , she 's dead .
Shelly 's dead .
We gotta bury her now .
[ thunderclap ]
[ low-pitched rumbling ]
Linda 's still sleeping .
- I think once her leg 's - - - I 'm getting out of here .
Scott , we can 't take Linda anywhere with her leg like that .
We don 't even know if there is any other way back besides the bridge .
Well , maybe there 's a hiking trail , or an old road ,
or some other way around the cliff .
I mean , there 's gotta be another way besides the bridge .
Listen to me .
Linda cannot walk with her leg like that . She can 't even stand up .
Well , then we 'll leave her here until we can send somebody back .
What are you , crazy ?
- Scott - - - Look , I 'm gettin ' out !
I don 't care what happens to her .
She 's your girlfriend . You take care of her .
I 'm getting the hell out of here right now .
J
[ distorted voice ] Soon all of you will be like me
and then we will lock you up in the cellar !
[ cackling ]
[ cackling continues ]
[ shrieks , cackles ]
[ screams ] My God , Ash !
Ash .
- Oh my God . - Help me .
Yes , help me . Yes .
- Did you fall , or what ? - [ giggles ]
[ moans ]
Scotty , you 're gonna be okay .
You 're gonna be just fine , you 'll see .
- [ clatter ] - [ evil giggling ]
Ash , it 's not gonna let us leave .
Cheryl - - Cheryl was right .
- We 're all gonna die here . - No , we 're not gonna die .
We 're all gonna die , all of us .
No , we 're not gonna die .
We 're not gonna die ! We 're gonna get outta here !
Now listen to me , Scotty . Is there a way around the bridge ?
Scotty !
Listen to me , please ! For God 's sake !
- Scott ! - [ moans ]
- Come on . - Ash ...
Ash , I don 't wanna die .
You 're not gonna leave me , are you , Ash ?
- Are you ? - " l don 't wanna die .
You 're not gonna leave me here , are you ?
Are you , Ash ? " [ laughs ]
Scotty , now come on ! Listen to me , for God 's sake !
[ shouting ] Is there a way around the bridge ? !
There 's a way - - the trail .
But the trees , Ash ... they know .
Don 't you see , Ash ? They 're alive .
- [ evil giggling ] - [ screaming ]
[ laughing ]
Shut up ! Shut up , Linda !
[ laughing , giggling continue ]
- Shut up ! - [ giggling ]
[ giggling continues ]
Kill her . Kill her !
Kill her if you can , lover boy !
God forgive me , Linda .
[ giggling stops ]
Oh , Ash ... help me , please !
[ rifle clatters ]
Ash ?
Help me , please , Ash .
Oh , Ash , please don 't let them take me away again .
- Please . - No , I won 't .
- Please . - l won 't , I promise .
[ Cheryl , normal voice ] Ashley . Ashley , help me .
Let me out of here .
Ashley ? Ash , help me .
Let me out of here . I 'm - - I 'm all right now .
I 'm all right now , Ashley .
I 'm all right .
Unlock this chain and let me out .
Cheryl ?
[ distorted voice ] I 'm all right now , Ashley .
Come unlock the chain and let me out ! [ cackles ]
I 'm all right now .
It 's your sister Cheryl .
[ growling ]
Oh , you bastards !
Why are you torturing me like this ?
- Why ? ! - [ giggling ]
[ thunderclap ]
Shut up .
[ singsong voices ] We 're gonna get you
We 're gonna get you
Not another peep
Time to go to sleep
We 're ... [ giggles ]
Useless . Useless .
In time we 'll come for him , and then we 'll come for you .
[ shrieking ]
J
Here . Here .
Now the sun will be up in an hour or so ,
and we can all get out of here together - -
you , me , Linda , Shelly .
No , not Shelly . She ...
We 'll all be going home together .
Wouldn 't you like to be going home ?
I bet you 'd like that , wouldn 't you ?
J
- Scott ? - [ giggling ]
[ giggling continues ]
[ wolf howls ]
[ shrieks ]
[ yells ]
[ groans ]
[ yelling ]
[ velling , cackling ]
[ distorted voices ] Join us .
- Join us . - [ cackling ]
[ hysterical cackling ]
[ screams ]
[ breathing heavily ]
[ groaning ]
[ squeaks ]
[ motor whirring ]
[ motor turns off ]
[ chainsaw clatters ]
[ crying ] Oh , Linda .
J
[ grunting with effort ]
[ exhales ]
[ screams ]
[ screaming ]
- [ grunts ] - [ cackling ]
[ cackling continues ]
Come to me .
[ shrieks ]
[ gasping ]
[ screaming ]
Come on , get off .
[ screaming continues ]
[ screaming ]
[ panting ]
J
[ creaking ]
[ banging ]
[ banging continues ]
[ grunting ]
- Oh , God . - Help , Ashley . Ashley !
The door .
[ screaming ]
[ screams ]
The back door .
Shells - - where did I see that box of shells ?
[ dripping ]
[ groaning ]
[ screaming ]
[ music playing ]
[ coughing ]
[ Linda ] We 're gonna get you J
- We 're gonna get you . - Shut up , Linda .
- [ Scotty ] We 're all gonna die . - Shut up !
- All of us ! - Shut up .
- Ash , how sweet of you . - God forgive me , Linda .
[ man on tape ] ... through the act of bodily dismemberment .
- [ Scotty ] Hit her . - [ Linda ] I really love it .
- Hit her . - I 'll never take it off .
Hit it .
[ music playing , distorted ]
[ music stops ]
[ ticking ]
[ chiming ]
[ chiming louder ]
[ chiming , ticking continue ]
[ crashing ]
[ chiming , ticking stop ]
- [ cracking ] - [ gasps ]
[ heart pounding ]
[ gasps ]
[ wind howling ]
[ creaking ]
[ gasping ]
[ screaming ]
- [ panting ] - [ heart pounding ]
No !
- [ screams ] - [ roaring ]
[ distorted rumbling ]
[ creaking ]
[ muttering ] Oh , God ...
[ muttering ] There it is !
Come on , come on . Why are you torturing me like this ?
[ footsteps ]
- It 's nothing , man . - [ footsteps ]
[ ticking ]
Linda .
[ ticking stops ]
[ screaming ]
Join us ! Ashley , join us !
[ grunts ]
[ screaming ]
[ gasping ]
[ growling ]
Must die .
[ screaming ]
[ screeching ]
[ screaming fades ]
[ cracking ]
[ distorted noises ]
No .
[ moans ]
[ growls ]
[ screams ] No , no , no ! Oh , God !
[ distorted voice ] Join us .
Join us .
[ fading away ] Join us ...
[ ticking ]
[ birds chirping ]
[ birds chirping loudly ]
[ low-pitched rumble ]
[ screams ]